Until then, bye bye.
在那之前，再见了。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
Until now, we looked at various kinds of data types, right.
到目前为止，我们看了各种数据类型，对吧。
We looked at integers, floating point values,
我们看了整数、浮点值。
we looked at booleans,
我们看了布尔运算。
we looked at characters, we looked at strings.
我们看了字符，我们看了字符串。
The only data type which is missing until now is dates, right.
到目前为止，唯一缺少的数据类型是日期，对。
So, in this video, we would start exploring dates. Before Java 8,
所以，在这段视频中，我们将开始探索日期。在Java 8之前。
one of the constant problems with Java APIs is the implementation of date. They did not really have
在Java 8之前，Java APIs一直存在的问题之一就是日期的实现。他们并没有真正拥有
a good date API
一个好的日期API
and that's where a new implementation for dates is provided in Java 8.
而这正是Java 8中提供的新的日期实现的地方。
The new implementation was based on something called Joda Framework. So, this Joda was a very famous
这个新的实现是基于一个叫做Joda框架的东西。所以，这个Joda是一个非常著名的
alternative to the Java API for dates and Java 8 brought in some of the important concepts from Joda
的替代方案，而Java 8将Joda的一些重要概念引入了Java API本身。
into the Java API itself.
的一些重要概念引入到Java API本身。
So, we'll use that API, we will use the API which is introduced in Java 8 to discuss about dates in this
因此，我们将使用该API，我们将使用Java 8中引入的API来讨论本视频中的日期问题。
specific video.
具体的视频。
Java 8 brings in three most important classes. So, LocalDate, LocalDateTime, and LocalTime.
Java 8引入了三个最重要的类。所以，LocalDate、LocalDateTime和LocalTime。
These are the three classes which makes playing with date and time very easy.
这三个类使日期和时间的处理变得非常容易。
So, what is LocalDate, what is LocalDateTime, and what is LocalTime?
那么，什么是LocalDate，什么是LocalDateTime，以及什么是LocalTime？
So, date can hold a date. So, 10th October 2017, 15th December 2015. So, LocalDate can hold a date. LocalTime
所以，date可以持有一个日期。所以，2017年10月10日，2015年12月15日。所以，LocalDate可以容纳一个日期。而LocalTime
on the other hand can hold just the time. So, it can hold the time saying 23:25.
另一方面，它可以只保存时间。所以，它可以保存时间，如23:25。
That stands for 11:25 p.m or it can say 1:25, so 1:25 a.m. LocalDateTime
这代表晚上11:25，或者它可以说是1:25，所以是凌晨1:25。
can store both the date and the time. So, it can store things like, okay, 11:25 p.m on 10th December
可以同时存储日期和时间。因此，它可以存储诸如1985年12月10日晚上11点25分的事情。
of 1985.
1985年12月10日晚上11点25分。
Let's start exploring the API with LocalDate.
让我们开始探索LocalDate的API。
If I say, LocalDate now = LocalDate, there's a method called now( ).
如果我说，LocalDate now = LocalDate，有一个方法叫now( )。
This would fail.
这就会失败。
Now, why is this failing?
现在，为什么会失败呢？
Think about it.
想一想吧。
What could be the reasons, why it's failing?
会有什么原因导致失败呢？
LocalDate is in a package called Java.time. One of the important things is, JShell provides a few default
LocalDate是在一个叫做Java.time的包里。其中一件重要的事情是，JShell提供了一些默认的
imports.
导入。
So, if I do a /imports, it would show the default imports.
因此，如果我做一个
That's the reason why, we were able to use the BigDecimal class,
null
the String class without having a problem, because it was in the packages which are in the default imports.
However, this package, java.time.LocalDate, is not in the default imports. So, we would need to import it in. So, I will say
null
java.time.LocalDate. LocalDate
is now imported.
null
Now I'll execute the same statement and now, you would see that the LocalDate instance is now created.
You can see the value of it being printed in here.
null
It's saying 2018-02-01.
The same thing,
null
if I want to do with LocalDateTime, what would happen?
Think about it. LocalDateTime.now( ): error. Because we have to import that as well.
null
So, LocalDateTime.
The other option is to import everything together. So,
null
*,
right.
null
So, now I would be able to do a LocalDateTime.now( ).
So, the difference between LocateDate and LocalDateTime, as you can see in here, is LocalDateTime represents
null
both date and time whereas LocalDate only represents the date
and if I do a LocalTime, it represents only the time and you can see the different details that are
null
stored in here. In the next video,
we will start exploring all these three APIs a lot more.
null
Until then, bye bye.